Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin literary autograph collection, 1841-1993.
Rudin, Gail and Stephen autograph collection, 1841-1993
- Mitchison, Naomi: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. London., Mar. 3, no year (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Mumford, Lewis: Autograph letter to Jascha (?) Giller. Amenia, NY., Jul. 17, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  Regarding The Renewal of Life.
- Mumford, Lewis: Autograph letter to Wesley Hartley. Amenia, NY., Nov. 3, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Nabokov, Vladimir: Typed letter to Heather Mansell. Montreux, Switzerland., Nov. 25, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  Regarding covers for four books.
- Nash, Ogden: Typed letter to George Pluck. Baltimore, MD., Nov. 1, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Nash, Ogden: Autographed letters to Miriam, New York Times. North Hampton, NH., 1966 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  A cover letter accompanies a draft of a letter Nash sent to "The New York Times" regarding copyright protection for writers.
  Rudin # B-89
- Nims, John F.: Two letters to Wesley Hartley. Chicago, IL., 1995 (Box 10, Folder 6A)
- O'Casey, Sean: Autographed letter to Wallace Brockway. Devon., Nov. 10, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Refusing a request to recite from his plays. It "would force me to re-read all I've written - a work beyond my powers".
  Rudin # B-89A
- O'Casey, Sean: Autograph letter to Wesley Hartley. Torquay, England., Nov. 22, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- O'Casey, Sean: Typed letter to Edwin Burr Pettet, Esq. Torquay, Devon., Jun. 19, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  Letter explaining why he will not travel to Brandeis to lecture.
  Rudin # B-89B
- O. Henry: Autograph letter to James P. Crane. New York, NY., Dec. 7, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- O. Henry: Autograph manuscript., Dec. 4, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  The Charity that Ended at Home.
- O'Neill, Eugene: Autographed letter to Mrs. Foster. Province, MA., Apr. 2, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  O'Neill anticipates that his upcoming play, "The Hairy Ape" might spark strong criticism and asks Mrs. Foster to send letters rebutting the criticism to drama editors and any others who criticize.
  Rudin # B-90
- O'Neill, Eugene: Typed letter to Amram Schienfeld. Contra Costa, CA., Jun. 20, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Regarding Strange Interlude and Huntington's Disease. With photo, excerpt from Schienfeld book.
- Odets, Clifford: Autographed letters to addressed to "Dear Patchen". Los Angeles, CA., 1946 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  By turns, Odets both deals with the particulars and waxes philosophical.
  Rudin # B-89C
- Ogilvie, Elizabeth: Autograph letter and postcard to Wesley Hartley. Cushing, ME., Jun. 26, c. 1995; July 13, no year (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Olson, Charles: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Gloucester, MA., May 25, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 9A)
- O'Neill, Eugene: Typed letter to Mr. Karsnor, March 17, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 11A)
  Writes of his success and his gratitude to the public.
  Rudin # B-91
- Orczy, Baroness: Typed letter to Frederick Bason. Monte Carlo., May 3, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  The Baroness offers advice on starting a literary career.
  Rudin # B-92
- Oxenham, John (pseudonym of William Arthur Dunkerley): Typed letter to the editor of Nash's Magazine. Ealing., Aug. 17, 1912 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  Replying to his question about the public's taste for fiction.
  Rudin # B-93
- Pasternak, Boris: Autographed letter to Mrs. Olsson., Feb. 25, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  Compares himself to Salvatore Quasimodo who won the Nobel Prize for Literature in the year following Pasternak (1959).
  Rudin # B-94
- Paton, Alan: Autographed letter to Mrs. Allen and Elizabeth., Sep. 12, 1948 [?] (Box 10, Folder 14)
  Writes to Mrs. Allen that he has retired and is writing some verse. He writes Elizabeth that he believes "life and suffering are inseparable. Mentions "I am a confirmed and unrepentant believer in emotions (plus I hope some intellect)".
  Rudin # B-95
- Perelman, Sidney Joseph: 11 letters to Diane Boas, from various locations, 1975-1978 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  A series of amusing, flirtatious and downright ribald letters sent to a woman Perelman romanced in the last years of his life.
  Rudin # B-96
- Peterkin, Julia M.: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Fort Motte, SC., Apr. 4, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 15A)
- Porter, Katherine Anne: Autographed letter to Miss Brown., Oct. 27, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  Porter apologizes for not responding sooner and offers writing advice to the letter's recipient.
  Rudin # B-97
- Post, Emily: Autograph letter to Miss Greenall, April 14, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 2A)
  On what seems to be a partial form letter, Post responds to a question of proper etiquette regarding how to introduce someone.
  Rudin # B-97A
- Potter, Beatrix: Autograph letter to Ramsay Duff. Westmoreland., Jul. 13, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Regarding children's books.
- Pound, Ezra: Typed letter to editor of Chicago Tribune. Rapallo, Italy., Jan. 31, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Regarding editorial methods, publishers, and government spending.
- Puzo, Mario: Typed letter to John Black., No date (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Regarding The Godfather.
- (Queen, Ellery) Manfred B. Lee: Typed letter Roland West. New York City, NY., Mar. 24, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  Lee introduces himself as Ellery Queen and suggests that his novel be adapted for a motion picture.
  Rudin # B-98
- Reznikoff, Charles: Typed letter to Ronald Rayman. New York, NY., Dec. 21, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  Responds to a question about writing. "I should say offhand that a basic tendency to write is inherited".
  Rudin # B-99
- Rice, Alice Caldwell Hegan: Autographed letter to Mr. Cathcart. Louisville, KY., Mar. 21, 1902 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  "Mrs. Wiggs, herself, is a real character but the rest are, for the most part, imaginary."
  Rudin # B-99A
- Robertson, Eileen: Autographed letter to Wesley Hartley. London, England., Sep. 27 (Box 10, Folder 19A)
- Roethke, Theodore: Autographed letter to Allan Seager. State College, PA., Nov. 16, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  Writes about his life to his friend Seager.
  Rudin # B-100
- Ross, Alan John: Autographed letter to Wesley Hartley. (Box 10, Folder 20A)
- Sackville-West, Victoria: Autograph letter. Weald, Seven Oaks., Nov. 12, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Regarding success.
- Salinger, J.D.: Typed letter to Linda Barrett. Cornish, NH., Mar. 26, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  Answers a letter about writing. "There are no legitimate hints or tips about writing professionally."
  Rudin # B-100A
- Salinger, J.D.: Typed letter to Janet Eagleson. Cornish, NH., Mar. 16, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  Talks about his movie collection, gurus, what he's been writing since his last book, astrology, homeopathy, and other controversial subjects.
  Rudin # B-100B
- Sandberg, Carl: Signed postcard to Wayne Gard. Harbert, MI., Oct. 26, no year (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Regarding Lincoln: War Years.
- Saroyan, William: Typed letter to editor of Look magazine. Malibu, CA., Mar. 5, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Regarding death. With Saroyan envelope.
- Schulberg, Budd: Typed letter to Arthur and Rosemary., Oct. 18, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  Schulberg reminisces about his relationship with F. Scott Fitzgerald, announcing the publication of his memoir of Fitzgerald and other writers he knew in Hollywood, with inscribed copy of the book, "The Four Seasons of Success". (Book is catalogued individually).
  Rudin # B-100C
- Serling, Rod: Typed letter to Rita Goodman. Pacific Palisades, CA., Jan. 4, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- (Seuss, Dr.) Seuss Geisel, Theodor: Typed letter to Carol Orsag. La Jolla, CA., Mar. 29, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  Writes about how his first book, "Mulberry Street" came to be published.
  Rudin # B-101
- (Seuss, Dr.) Seuss Geisel, Theodor: Drawing (Box 10, Folder 24a)
  Original signed drawing of "The Cat" (from "The Cat In The Hat") from the neck up.
  Rudin # B-101A
- (Seuss, Dr.) Seuss Geisel, Theodor: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. La Jolla, California., June 3, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 9A)
  Seuss answers the question, is a college education necessary for a successful career in creative writing?
- Sewell, Elizabeth: Autograph letter to an editor. Bonchurch., Oct. 31, 1856 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Regarding manuscript by mutual friend.
- Shaw, George Bernard: Typed letter. London, England. (Box 10, Folder 25)
  Amusing printed response to an autograph collector.
- Shaw, George Bernard: Signed letter and manuscript addressed to "Dear Madam". Guildord, London., May 15, 1900; May 2, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  Shaw offers unsigned witty criticism of a play titled, "Thomas Ellwood's Guest". Accompanied by a letter mentioning the hypothesis of creative evolution put forward in the 1921 preface to "Back to Methuselah".
  Rudin # B-102
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autographed letter to Aleksander Marien Jasienski. London, England., Feb. 28, 1900 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  Shaw's opinions of his contemporaries and his forebears.
  Rudin # B-104
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autographed letter to St. John Hankin. London, England., Mar. 30, 1903 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  Writes about his bad experiences with publishers. "I am a very easy author to get on with."
  Rudin # B-105
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autograph letter to William Crooks. London., Feb. 27, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Regarding labor cause, Shaw's re-election.
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autographed letter to St. John Hankin. London, England., Jan. 17, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  Concerning Shaw's involvement in the translation of the play, "Les Trois Filles", by Franch playwright Eugene Brieux.
  Rudin # B-105AA
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autographed letter to Gilbert Murray. London, England., Jun. 21, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  Regarding finances and other content about his play, "You Never Can Tell".
  Rudin # B-105A
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autographed letter to Gilbert Murray. London, England., Nov. 29, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  Discusses the premiere of his play, "Major Barbara".
  Rudin # B-105B
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autographed letter to Erica Cotterill. Ayot, St. Lawrence and Welwyn, Hertsforshire., Dec. 14-16, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  One of the first letters by Shaw to Cotterill, a flirtatious and precocious child/woman who carried on an extensive correspondence with Shaw.
  Rudin # B-106
- Shaw, George Bernard: Typed manuscript., ca. 1908 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  Manuscript written by Lawrence Hockey mentioning Shaw's assistance in helping Welsh poet William Henry Davies publish his book, "Autobiography of a Super-Tramp". Shaw has made a number of editorial corrections and additions to the manuscript.
  Rudin # B-106A
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autographed letter to Erica Cotterill. London, England., Jan. 31, 1908 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  Regarding her plays and performances.
  Rudin # B-107
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autograph letter to My dear Emerica (Erica Cotterill). London, England., Apr. 22, 1908 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  Shaw writes to Cotterill telling her to stop being so annoying and flirtatious.
  Rudin # B-108
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autographed letter to Mr Dear Emerica (Erica Cotterill). London, England., Oct. 13, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Another letter to Cotterill.
  Rudin # B-109
- Shaw, George Bernard: Typed letter to Ernest Rhys, Everyman's Library. London, Mar. 28, 1912 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  Shaw refuses to write a preface for the novel "Yeast".
  Rudin # B-109A
- Shaw, George Bernard: Typed letter to George Allen and Unwin Ltd. London, England., Nov. 13, 1914 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Replying to an enquiry about reprinting his essay, "Common Sense about the War", that has been long delayed.
  Rudin # B-110
- Shaw, George Bernard: Copy of the "New Statesman" and the "War Supplement". Rudin # B-110, Nov. 14, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Shaw, George Bernard: Signed correspondence card to Ernest Gitsham. London, England., Nov. 22, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Shaw urges Gitsham to exclude his plays from the school curriculum.
  Rudin # B-111
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autograph letter to editor of The Bookman. Dublin., Oct. 14, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Regarding teaching.
- Shaw, George Bernard: Typed letter to W.S. Kennedy, The Incorporated Stage Society. London., Jun. 25, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  Shaw discusses Henry James's abilities as a playwright and a possible production of his own new play, "Heartbreak House".
  Rudin # B-111A
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autographed letter addressed to "Dear Sir". Kenmare. Co. Kerry., Aug. 10, 1919 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  Giving excellent advice to the recipient about publishing a manuscript sent to Shaw.
  Rudin # B-112
- Shaw, George Bernard: Signed document. London, England., Feb. 9, 1921 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  License fees and performance provisions for "Arms and the Man".
  Rudin # B-113
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autographed note., May 14, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  "Here is a woman who declares that I have given her help, self knowledge, strength, and a better understanding. And the result is that she collects autographs!"
  Rudin # B-113A
- Shaw, George Bernard: Signed letter to Gwen John. Somerset., Apr. 8, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  Letter offering advice to an aspiring playwright.
  Rudin # B-113B
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autograph postcard to Ben Turner. London., Jul. 2, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Regarding how to write in a dialect.
- Shaw, George Bernard: Signed document., Oct. 17, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  License fees and performance provisions for "Arms and the Man" and "The Dark Lady of the Sonnets".
  Rudin # B-114
- Shaw, George Bernard: Signed document. London, England., Jan. 8, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  License fees and performance provisions for "Fanny's First Play".
  Rudin # B-114A
- Shaw, George Bernard: Signed document. London, England., Jan. 27, 1925 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  License fees and performance provisions for "Candida".
  Rudin # B-115
- Shaw, George Bernard: Typed letter to George S. Viereck. London, England., Oct. 7, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  "Our intercourse henceforward is not for publication".
  Rudin # B-115A
- Shaw, George Bernard: Signed document. London, England., Jan. 11, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  License fees and performance provisions for "Pygmalian".
  Rudin # B-116
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autograph letter to Sylvia Pankhurst. "On the road"., Apr. 20, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Regarding mortality of mothers and children during birth.
- Shaw, George Bernard: Typed letter to Elbridge Adams. London., Apr. 30, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Regarding collector's edition.
- Shaw, George Bernard: Typed letter to Gilbert Miller. Malvern., Jul. 24, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  Discusses the initial production of "The Millionairess".
  Rudin # B-117A
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autographed note, January 3, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 12a)
  Amusing and characteristic"autobiographical" note signed on the mount of his photograph.
  Rudin # B-117D
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autograph letter from H.L. Bohm to Shaw. London., Dec. 15, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Regarding Pygmalion.
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autograph postcard to Mrs. G.E. Minto. London., Oct. 4, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  Advice and encouragement.
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autograph letter on back of "open letter"., Dec. 19, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  Regarding open letter.
- Shaw, George Bernard: Typed letter to M. Storm Jameson, Feb. 13, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  Shaw declines Jameson's appeal to contribute to the Red Cross, evidently by donating one of his manuscripts to be sold for its benefit.
  Rudin # B-117
- Shaw, George Bernard: Typed letter to Joseph Z. Dalinda. London., Dec. 8, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  Regarding why bureaucracies resist change.
- Shaw, George Bernard: Typed letter to EHW Meyerstein, Magdalen College, Oxford. London., Oct. 13, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  Writes about the widow of playwright St. John Emile Clavering Hankin; also discusses literary standards.
  Rudin # B-117B
- Shaw, George Bernard: Signed note. London., Nov. 28, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  Short note written under a pre-printed message providing his reasoning for not providing autographs. Included is his book, "Bernard Shaw His Life and Personality". Book includes additional items including autographs of cast members of a play. (Book is catalogued individually)
  Rudin # B-117C
- Shaw, George Bernard: Typed letter to George Sylvester Viereck. London., Nov. 18, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  Regarding poetry by Viereck's son.
- Shaw, George Bernard: Signed correspondence card. Ayot St. Lawrence and Welwyn, Hertsforshire., Jun. 18, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  Shaw authorizing Gertrude Lawrence to broadcast any part of his writings in exchange for a pair of mittens.
  Rudin # B-118
- Shaw, George Bernard: Autographed letter to Sylvia Lyons. Ayot St. Lawrence, Welwyn Hertsforshire, Mar. 17, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  Warns Lyons not to come to visit him and to bring her son to the zoo instead. With manuscript shorthand fragment of the opening scene of "The Dark Lady of the Sonnets". Also included is Supplementary Material (Original purchased by another buyer) of a letter written by Shaw in Pittman shorthand describing how he uses shorthand for his writing.
  Rudin # B-119
- Simenon, Georges: Typed letter to Steve Juscik., Jul. 28, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  Simenon explains why he would not read the works of others.
  Rudin # B-119A
- Simon, Neil: Autograph letter to Mr. Cooper., No date (Box 5, Folder 21)
  Regarding "lasting importance".
- Simon, Neil: Typed letter to Robert Hudson., Jan. 17, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  Informs Hudson of his favorite plays and the length of time it takes to write them. With a copy of the text of Hudson's letter to Simon.
  Rudin # B-120
- Sinclair, Upton: Autograph letter to Edmund Stedman. New York, NY., c. Nov. 1900 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  Regarding novel-in-progress.
- Sinclair, Upton: Typed letter to Mr. Greenway. Pasadena, CA., May 11, 1925 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  "I helped to spread distrust of our capitalist press."
  Rudin # B-121
- Sinclair, Upton: Typed letter to H.W. Pointon. Long Beach, CA., May 31, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  Regarding censorship of Oil.
- Singer, Isaac B.: Typed manuscript and photograph. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  A review of one of Harold Pinter's most famous plays "The Homecoming".
  Rudin # B-122
- Singer, Isaac B.: Typed and autographed manuscripts. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  An essay explaining why he writes his stories in Yiddish (with corrected typescript, unsigned, heavily edited and annotated by Singer). Probably presented at a conference. (The AMs is not complete -it lacks pages 5,6,and 7 of the TMs).
  Rudin # B-123
- Singer, Isaac Bashevis: Typed letter to Dusty Sklar. New York, NY., Jul. 7, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  Advice on writing.
- Singer, Isaac B.: Souvenir typescript., Nov. 6, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  Extract from "U.S. News and World Report" - "A good writer should try his best to be clear."
  Rudin # B-124
- Slaughter, Frank: Autograph letter to Mr. Hartley., Apr. 16, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Regarding education and writing. With article by Slaughter.
- Smith, AJM: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. East Lansing, MI., Nov. 4, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 19A)
- Smith, Chard Powers: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Arlington, VT., Sep. 19, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 19B)
- Smith, James: Poem to Mrs. O. Unsigned., Feb. 15, 1838 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  Poem sent "to Mrs. O" on her 50th birthday entitled "Withering Satire".
  Rudin # B-125
- Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr: Typed letter to Mr. Elie Wiesel. Cavendish, VT., Aug. 4, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Regarding invitation to conference of Nobel Laureates.
- Spender, Stephen: Typed manuscript., 1957 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  Essay titled, "London Letter". Discusses the current state of British literature and the literary and political merits of previous generations.
  Rudin # B-126
- Spender, Stephen: Three autographed letters to Mr. Schaire, editor in chief of "Art and Antiques" magazine. France and London., 1991 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  A file consisting of three autograph letters (including envelopes) relating to Spender's article on "Henry Moore's Shelter Drawings"; the first draft of the manuscript, to be printed in "Art and Antiques" magazine, is included with Spender's corrections and illustrations of Moore's art.
  Rudin # B-127
- Spillane, Mickey: Typed quote, signed., Apr./May 1990 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  "I like people to enjoy what I've done…Writing should be fun". Excerpted from a magazine article.
  Rudin # B-128
- Steen, Margeurite: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley., Oct. 2, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 23A)
- Stein, Gertrude: Autographed letter to Frank Crowinshield. Paris, France., ca. May 1925 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  Regarding the publication of her work, "Making of Americans".
  Rudin # B-128A
- Stein, Gertrude: Autographed letter to Marcella Burns. Bilignin, Par Belley, Ain, France., ca. 1935 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  Tells of her trip to the U.S. and how glad she is to be back to the garden, dogs and nightingales.
  Rudin # B-129
- Steinbeck, John: Autographed letter to Murray. NY., Dec. 4 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  An exuberant tirade against Christmas and its disruptive effect on his writing.
  Rudin # B-130
- Steinbeck, John: Autographed documents to Harry Thornton Moore. Pacific Grove, CA., Feb. 15, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  Postcard mentions a book he is currently writing and one he plans to write. Also included is a pamphlet, "John Steinbeck and His Novels", and a 1949 letter from a bookstore offering this and other Steinbeck letters for the first time.
  Rudin # B-131
- Steinbeck, John: Autographed postcard to Jake Zeitlin. Los Gatos, CA., ca. 1937 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  Steinbeck describes his method for writing, "Of Mice and Men".
  Rudin # B-132
- Steinbeck, John: Autographed letter to William Ward Beecher. Pacific Grove, CA., Dec. 28, [1948] (Box 11, Folder 29)
  Expressing regrets at being unable to purchase property because "divorce has bankrupted me"; additionally, he recounts a story connected to a gift he gave the recipient's wife.
  Rudin # B-133
- Steinbeck, John: Typed letter to Ballard Hadman. New York., Apr. 4, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  Steinbeck writes about a writer's use of words.
  Rudin # B-134
- Steinbeck, John: Autographed letters to Christine Schunck., 1956 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  Two letters addressing his thoughts on words, his two sons, his lineage and his latest book.
  Rudin # B-135
- Steinbeck, John: Typed letter to Martha C. Johnson. New York, NY., Feb. 20, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  Regarding The Short Reign of Pippin IV: a Fabrication.
- Steinbeck, John: Autographed letter to Edgar J. Bracco. New York., Mar. 7, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  "Styles come and go. I'm told I'm out of fashion now but I can't remember when I wasn't."
  Rudin # B-136
- Steinbeck, John: Signed document., Jul. 11, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  A license for the stage adaptation of "The Short Reign of Pippin IV"; accompanied by an unsigned supplementary document.
  Rudin # B-137
- Steinbeck, John: Typed letter to Vernon Reyman. NY., Nov. 21, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  Acknowledges congratulations for winning the Nobel Prize.
  Rudin # B-138
- Steinbeck, John: Typed letter to Alex and Doris. Long Island, NY., Jun. 24, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Regarding production of Of Mice and Men.
- Stevenson, Robert Louis: Autograph letter to F.W. Dover. Upolu, Samoa., Jun. 20, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  Regarding being poor.
- Street, Julian Leonard: Typed letter to Ernest Kroll. New York, NY., Mar. 8, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Styron, William: Autograph letter to Mr. Hartley. Roxbury, CT., Mar. 13, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Sutzkever, Abraham: Beneath the Trees. (Book), 2003 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Swinnerton, Frank: signed letter to Wesley Hartley., Sep. 23, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  Swinnerton responds to questions concerning his opinion of the value of schooling.
  Rudin # B-138AA
- Symons, Julian: Manuscript, notes and clippings., 1978 (Box 15)